Guide to the photograph album Voyages on RMS Maloja and SS Kaisar-I-Hind from the Hisham Khatib Collection AD.MC.030_ref163
Akkasah: Photography Archive (NYU Abu Dhabi)
Voyages on RMS Maloja and SS Kaisar-I-Hind - Hisham Khatib Collection
1927-1930
Akkasah: Photography Archive (NYU Abu Dhabi)
AD.MC.030_ref163
100 Photographic Prints 29 x 18 cm album containing ca. 100 prints mainly in Egypt with others in India and Australia
Photograph album containing ca. 100 prints taken mainly in Egypt, India and Australia between 1924 and 1930 during voyages on the ships RMS Maloja and SS Kaisar-I-Hind. The album's creator (Roy) is pictured as the pianist of the S.S. Kaisar-I-Hind Ship's band "Kaisar Kittens" and as a member of the RMS Maloja's orchestra The Equator Band. The album includes photographs of Prince Henry, Duke of Gloucester in October 1928 before the start of his tour of Africa. The album belongs to the Hisham Khatib Collection.
Object Digital copy only - 030_ref163
Photographic Prints; Boats/Ships; Musicians; India; Egypt; Australia; Travel
- Front outside cover of photo album Voyages on RMS Maloja and SS Kaisar-I-Hind - Hisham Khatib Collection, Circa 1924-1930; ref163_000001; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref163)
  English Writing
- Front inside cover of photo album Voyages on RMS Maloja and SS Kaisar-I-Hind - Hisham Khatib Collection., Circa 1924-1930; ref163_000002; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref163)
- Prince Henry, Duke of Gloucester boarding the S.S. Kaisar-I-Hind for the start of an African tour, and a garden Fete in Marseilles., October 1928; ref163_000003; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref163)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; English Writing; Gardens; Men; Uniforms; Boats/Ships; Crowds; Outdoors; Buildings; Marseille, France; Royalty; Group Portraits; Henry, Prince, Duke of Gloucester, 1900-1974
- Views of Mount Stromboli erupting and RMS Maloja off the coast of Gibraltar., October 1928; ref163_000004; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref163)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; English Writing; Mountains/Hills; Boats/Ships; Seas; Coast; Stromboli, Italy; Gibraltar; Landscapes
- Views of Mount Stromboli, Malta, and Messina., Circa 1928; ref163_000005; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref163)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; English Writing; Coast; Seas; Mountains/Hills; Mediterranean Sea; Buildings; Stromboli, Italy; Malta; Messina, Italy; Ports; Landscapes
- Views of Bombay (Mumbai), Aden, and Suez., Circa 1924-1930; ref163_000006; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref163)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; English Writing; Suez, Egypt; Mumbai/Bombay, India; Aden, Yemen; Canals; Buildings; Offices; Architecture; Hotels; Landscapes
- Views of Bombay (Mumbai) and Gibraltar., Circa 1924-1930; ref163_000007; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref163)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; English Writing; Mumbai/Bombay, India; Museums; Railways; Buildings; Architecture; Seas; Gibraltar; Umbrellas/Parasols; Clocks/Watches; Statues/Sculptures; Coast; Landscapes
- Prince Henry, Duke of Gloucester boarding the S.S. Kaisar-I-Hind in Marseilles, views of Stromboli and the RMS Maloja., Circa 1928; ref163_000008; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref163)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; English Writing; Boats/Ships; Men; Mountains/Hills; Seas; Marseille, France; Stromboli, Italy; Royalty; Group Portraits; Landscapes; Henry, Prince, Duke of Gloucester, 1900-1974
- The album's creator (Roy) as pianist of the S.S. Kaisar-I-Hind Ship's band "Kaisar Kittens", Roy and two other men at the Breach Candy swimming baths (Mumbai), and the H.M.S. Enterprise (D52) off the coast of Aden., Circa 1924-1930; ref163_000009; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref163)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Boats/Ships; Men; Tuxedos; Musical Instruments; Pianos; Coast; Aden, Yemen; Mountains/Hills; Seas; Mumbai/Bombay, India; Swimming Pools; Percussion Instruments; Musicians; Group Portraits; Landscapes
- Roy and a group at a picnic in Juhu (India), on the deck of RMS Maloja, and a man on the S.S. Kaisar-I-Hind., Circa 1928; ref163_000010; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref163)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; English Writing; Outdoors; Men; Women; Juhu, Mumbai, India; Gardens; Boats/Ships; Picnic; Maritime/Nautical Outfits; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Umbrellas/Parasols; Group Portraits; Hats
- Group portraits in Juhu, India., Circa 1928; ref163_000011; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref163)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Juhu, Mumbai, India; Mumbai/Bombay, India; Picnic; Beaches; Gardens; Outdoors; Buildings; Men; Women; Umbrellas/Parasols; Hats; Bathing Suits/Swimsuits; Architecture; Group Portraits; Individual Portraits
- Views of Port Said and a ship docked in Bombay (Mumbai)., Circa 1924-1930; ref163_000012; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref163)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Mumbai/Bombay, India; Ports; Port Said, Egypt; Boats/Ships; Buildings; Hotels; Advertisements; Flags; Architecture
- Coal workers in Aden, the entrance to the Botanical Gardens in Marseilles and the anchor chain at the side of a ship., Circa 1924-1930; ref163_000013; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref163)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Aden, Yemen; Boats/Ships; Workers; Gardens; Buildings; Men; Women; Marseille, France; Prams/Buggies/Strollers
- Roy with a group on RMS Maloja, and on the S.S. Kaisar-I-Hind., Circa 1924-1930; ref163_000014; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref163)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Men; Boats/Ships; Mumbai/Bombay, India; Maritime/Nautical Outfits; Group Portraits; Uniforms; Military/Soldiers
- Maintenance on the S.S. Kaisar-I-Hind, a group in costumes and the ship's band 'Kaisar Kittens' at baths in Bombay (Mumbai)., Circa 1924-1930; ref163_000015; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref163)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Boats/Ships; Costumes; Men; Women; Mumbai/Bombay, India; Bathing Suits/Swimsuits; Workers; Group Portraits; Bathing Suits/Swimsuits; Swimming Pools; Workers
- Views of Port Said and Port Tewfik., Circa 1924-1930; ref163_000016; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref163)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Port Said, Egypt; Streets/Roads; Buildings; Architecture; Outdoors; Ports; Hotels; Advertisements; Cars/Trucks; Transportation; Carriages/Coaches; Regional/National Dress; Men; Monuments/Memorials
- RMS Maloja entering Port Said, ships taking on coal and in the harbour at Port Said, and the Suez Canal., Circa 1924-1930; ref163_000017; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref163)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Boats/Ships; Suez, Egypt; Canals; Ports; Port Said, Egypt; Buildings; Architecture; Workers; Camels; Men; Docks/Piers/Jetties; Transportation
- Statue of Ferdinand de Lesseps, Ballard Pier in Bombay (Mumbai), English Church at Port Said and Tawfiq Mosque., Circa 1924-1930; ref163_000018; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref163)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Statues/Sculptures; Port Said, Egypt; Docks/Piers/Jetties; Mumbai/Bombay, India; English Writing; Mosques; Churches; Religious Sites; Architecture; Buildings; Lesseps, Ferdinand de (Marie, Comte), 1805-1894
- Views of Port Said, Suez, and the Sydney Heads., Circa 1924-1930; ref163_000019; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref163)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Boats/Ships; Lighthouses; Suez, Egypt; Port Said, Egypt; Ports; Docks/Piers/Jetties; Architecture; Buildings; Sydney, Australia; Hotels; Advertisements; Monuments/Memorials
- Roy and the 'Kaisar Kittens' band at Juhu Restaurant (India), with a group from the RMS Maloja and a portrait in Melbourne., 1929, February 1930; ref163_000020; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref163)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Juhu, Mumbai, India; Restaurants/bars; Beaches; Group Portraits; Men; Individual Portraits; Outdoors; Bathing Suits/Swimsuits; Musical Instruments; Melbourne, Australia; Drinks/Beverages; Percussion Instruments
- Roy and another crew member on the RMS Maloja, a ship leaving Melbourne, Roy standing in the sea in Melbourne beach., Circa 1930; ref163_000021; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref163)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Boats/Ships; Men; Individual Portraits; Group Portraits; Bathing Suits/Swimsuits; Outdoors; Maritime/Nautical Outfits; Buildings; Docks/Piers/Jetties; Melbourne, Australia; Uniforms; Seas; Military/Soldiers
- Group portrait of Maloja Swimming Club members, crowds watching entertainment on deck., Circa 1929-1930; ref163_000022; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref163)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Men; Group Portraits; Beaches; Boats/Ships; Crowds; Performance Plays; Unknown Locations; Bathing Suits/Swimsuits; Costumes
- Games and entertainment on the deck of the RMS Maloja and Roy with the ship's orchestra, The Equator Band., Circa 1930; ref163_000023; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref163)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; English Writing; Boats/Ships; Men; Women; Crowds; Group Portraits; Gatherings; Musical Instruments; Swimming Pools; Costumes; Maritime/Nautical Outfits; Swimming; Performance Plays; Orchestra; Unknown Locations; Uniforms; Military/Soldiers
- Group portrait of the Equator Band on the RMS Maloja, the band processioning and games on the ship's deck., Circa 1929-1930; ref163_000024; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref163)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; English Writing; Maritime/Nautical Outfits; Group Portraits; Men; Swimming; Swimming Pools; Boats/Ships; Parades/Processions; Musical Instruments; Marching Band; Percussion Instruments; Unknown Locations; Uniforms; Military/Soldiers
- Members of The Equator Band on the RMS Maloja and a the ship leaving Melbourne for England., Circa 1929-1930; ref163_000025; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref163)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Melbourne, Australia; Boats/Ships; Photographic Prints; Seas; English Writing; Men; Group Portraits; Musical Instruments; Individual Portraits; Transportation
- Performance and entertainment scenes on the RMS Maloja., Circa 1929-1930; ref163_000026; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref163)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Boats/Ships; Costumes; Gatherings; Men; Women; Performance Plays; Swimming Pools; Unknown Locations; Transportation; Group Portraits
- Entertainment on the RMS Maloja, men on the deck of a sailing boat and a group portrait in Bondi., Circa 1929-1930; ref163_000027; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref163)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Boats/Ships; Sydney, Australia; Gatherings; Group Portraits; Costumes; Performance Plays; Musical Instruments; Transportation
- A group portrait taken in Adelaide, a man and a woman posing outdoors and a view of Manly Beach., Circa 1929-1930; ref163_000028; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref163)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; English Writing; Group Portraits; Sydney, Australia; Adelaide, Australia; Men; Women; Beaches; Buildings; Outdoors; Boats/Ships; Umbrellas/Parasols; Hats
- Group portraits taken in Adelaide and a view of a ferry in Sydney., Circa 1929-1930; ref163_000029; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref163)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; English Writing; Adelaide, Australia; Sydney, Australia; Boats/Ships; Group Portraits; Men; Women; Outdoors; Food; Tea/Coffee; Cars/Trucks; Transportation; Picnic; Hats; Bags/Purses; Gloves
- Portraits taken at Sydney harbour, Bondi, and on the RMS Maloja., Circa 1929-1930; ref163_000030; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref163)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; English Writing; Group Portraits; Individual Portraits; Men; Women; Boats/Ships; Outdoors; Sydney, Australia; Melbourne, Australia; Children; Signatures
- Views of ships, a man posing outdoors and views on the deck of a yacht., Circa 1929-1930; ref163_000031; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref163)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Boats/Ships; Men; Individual Portraits; Outdoors; Unknown Locations; Transportation; Group Portraits
- Blank page., Circa 1924-1930; ref163_000032; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref163)
- RMS Maloja ship orchestra, The Equator Band, on top of a stack of photographs., Circa 1924-1930; ref163_000033; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref163)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits; Men; Musical Instruments; Percussion Instruments; Boats/Ships; Orchestra; Unknown Locations
- Blank page., Circa 1924-1930; ref163_000034; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref163)
- Blank page., Circa 1924-1930; ref163_000035; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref163)
- The RMS Maloja ship's orchestra., November 1926; ref163_000036; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref163)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Tuxedos; Musical Instruments; Percussion Instruments; Pianos; Group Portraits; Violins; Orchestra; Unknown Locations
- RMS Maloja's orchestra., Circa 1924-1930; ref163_000037; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref163)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Men; Group Portraits; Orchestra; Musical Instruments; Percussion Instruments; Boats/Ships; Unknown Locations; Signatures
- Group portrait of the Maloja Swimming Club on the beach in Melbourne., Circa 1929-1930; ref163_000038; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref163)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Group Portraits; Beaches; Melbourne, Australia; Bathing Suits/Swimsuits; Signatures
- Roy and another man sitting on a garden seat in Glenelg., 1930; ref163_000039; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref163)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Outdoors; Gardens; Group Portraits; Australia
- Roy and another man on the deck of the RMS Maloja., 27 August 1929; ref163_000040; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref163)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Boats/Ships; Group Portraits; Unknown Locations; Uniforms; Transportation; Signatures; Military/Soldiers
- A portrait of Roy and another man on the deck of the RMS Maloja., Circa 1924-1930; ref163_000041; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref163)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Men; Group Portraits; Boats/Ships; Maritime/Nautical Outfits; Unknown Locations; Signatures
- Portrait of Roy on the RMS Maloja., Circa 1924-1930; ref163_000042; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref163)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; English Writing; Individual Portraits; Boats/Ships; Unknown Locations; Signatures; Men
- A member of the RMS Maloja's orchestra., Circa 1924-1930; ref163_000043; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref163)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; English Writing; Boats/Ships; Orchestra; Musical Instruments; Percussion Instruments; Unknown Locations; Men; Uniforms; Military/Soldiers
- Ship's orchestra on the RMS Maloja., 4 November 1929; ref163_000044; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref163)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; English Writing; Boats/Ships; Group Portraits; Orchestra; Percussion Instruments; Men; Musical Instruments; Brass Instruments; Unknown Locations; Signatures; Uniforms; Military/Soldiers
- Ship's orchestra on the RMS Maloja., Circa 1924-1930; ref163_000045; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref163)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Photographic Prints; Men; Group Portraits; Orchestra; Boats/Ships; Uniforms; Musical Instruments; Percussion Instruments; Brass Instruments; Unknown Locations; Military/Soldiers
- Ship's orchestra on the RMS Maloja., Circa 1924-1930; ref163_000046; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref163)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Boats/Ships; Orchestra; Men; Group Portraits; Musical Instruments; Percussion Instruments; Uniforms; Brass Instruments; Unknown Locations; Military/Soldiers
- A group portrait of the RMS Maloja's band wearing tuxedos., November 1928; ref163_000047; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref163)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Men; Group Portraits; English Writing; Boats/Ships; Orchestra; Tuxedos; Musical Instruments; Pianos; Brass Instruments; String Instruments; Unknown Locations; Signatures
- Theatrical performance on the RMS Maloja., Circa 1924-1930; ref163_000048; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref163)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Crowds; Boats/Ships; Costumes; Maritime/Nautical Outfits; Men; Performance Plays; Unknown Locations; Group Portraits
- A portrait of Roy in a swimsuit, taken on Melbourne beach., 1930; ref163_000049; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref163)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Bathing Suits/Swimsuits; Beaches; Seas; Buildings; Melbourne, Australia; Men; Signatures
- A portrait of Roy in a swimsuit, taken on Melbourne beach., 1930; ref163_000050; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref163)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Bathing Suits/Swimsuits; Beaches; Boats/Ships; Docks/Piers/Jetties; Melbourne, Australia; Men; Signatures
- View of a P&O ship in the Suez Canal., Circa 1924-1930; ref163_000051; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref163)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Boats/Ships; Suez, Egypt; Canals; Transportation; Water
- View of the RMS Majola and a boat in Melbourne., 1930; ref163_000052; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref163)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Boats/Ships; Seas; Melbourne, Australia; Transportation; Water
- View of the sea from a ship., Circa 1924-1930; ref163_000053; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref163)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Boats/Ships; Seas; Unknown Locations
- The RMS Maloja., Circa 1924-1930; ref163_000054; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref163)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Boats/Ships; Seas; Unknown Locations; Transportation
- The RMS Maloja., Circa 1924-1930; ref163_000056; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref163)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Boats/Ships; Seas; Unknown Locations; Transportation
- The RMS Maloja., Circa 1924-1930; ref163_000055; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref163)
- Performance and entertainment onboard the RMS Maloja., Circa 1924-1930; ref163_000057; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref163)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Boats/Ships; Men; Performance Plays; Costumes; Maritime/Nautical Outfits; Crowds; Unknown Locations; Group Portraits
- Crowds standing at the dock as the RMS Majola prepares to sail., Circa 1924-1930; ref163_000058; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref163)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Crowds; Boats/Ships; Docks/Piers/Jetties; Unknown Locations; Transportation; Group Portraits
- An ocean sunfish (Mola Mola) taken from the side of the boat., Circa 1924-1930; ref163_000059; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref163)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Boats/Ships; Water; Seas; Animals; Unknown Locations; Fish
- Unclear image., Circa 1924-1930; ref163_000060; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref163)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Unknown Locations; Boats/Ships